So far, you've just started a conversation to
到目前为止 我们只是介绍了
set the stage for what we'd like to accomplish.
我们要实现的目标
We'll use the remainder of this lesson to specify
我们将在这节课的后续部分
a rigorous definition for the reinforcement learning problem.
对强化学习问题进行充分定义
For context, we'll work with the example of a recycling robot from the Sutton textbook.
介绍下背景信息 我们将使用 Sutton 教科书中的回收机器人作为讲解示例
So consider a robot that's designed for picking up empty soda cans.
有一个机器人专门用来拾起空的易拉罐
The robot is equipped with arms to grab the cans and runs on a rechargeable battery.
该机器人配有机械臂 并安装了可充电电池
There's a docking station set up in one corner of the room and
房间的某个角落配有充电基站
the robot has to sit at the station if it needs to recharge its battery.
要为电池充电 机器人必须坐到该基站上
Say, you're trying to program this robot to collect
假设你尝试让该机器人
empty soda cans without human intervention.
在没有人类干预的情况下收集空的易拉罐
In particular, you want the robot to be able to
尤其是 你希望机器人能够自己判断
decide for itself when it needs to recharge its battery.
何时需要充电
And whenever it doesn't need to recharge,
当它不需要充电时
you want it to focus on collecting as many soda cans as possible.
你希望它能专门收集更多的易拉罐
So let's see if we can frame this as a reinforcement learning problem.
我们看看能否将此问题构建成强化学习问题
We'll begin with the actions.
先从动作开始
We'll say the robot is capable of executing three potential actions.
假设机器人能够执行三个潜在的动作
It can search the room for cans,
能够在房间中搜索易拉罐
it can head to the docking station to recharge its battery,
能够前往充电基站充电
or it can stay put in the hopes that someone brings it a can.
或者保持不动并等待其他人扔进去一个易拉罐
We refer to the set of possible actions as the action space,
我们将这组可能的动作称之为动作空间
and it's common to denote it with a script A. All right.
通常表示为手写体 A
What about the states?
状态呢？
Remember, the states are just the context
状态是提供给智能体的背景信息
provided to the agent for making intelligent actions.
帮助智能体做出合理的动作
So the state, in this case,
因此这里的状态
could be the charge left on the robot's battery.
可能是机器人电池的电量
For simplicity, we'll assume that the battery has one of two states.
为了简单起见 我们假设电池有两个状态
One corresponding to a high amount of charge left,
一个对应剩余电量很高
and the other corresponding to a low amount of charge.
另一个对应剩余电量很低
We refer to the set of possible states as
我们将一组可能的状态称之为状态空间
the state space and it's common to denote with a script S.
通常表示为手写体 S
So intuition tells us that if
根据常识
the robot has a high amount of charge left on its battery,
如果机器人的剩余电量很高
we'd like it to know to actively search for the room for cans.
我们希望它能积极地在房间内寻找易拉罐
Searching the room should use up a lot of energy but this
搜索房间会用掉很多功耗
doesn't matter so much because the battery has a lot of charge anyway.
但是没关系 因为电池还有很多电量
But if the state is low,
但是如果电量很低
searching for cans has pretty high risk because
搜索易拉罐的风险就很高
the battery could get depleted mid-search and
因为在搜索中途电量可能会耗尽
then the robot would be stranded and that wouldn't be so
机器人会困在途中
good because we don't want to have to come to its rescue.
这样不太理想 因为我们不希望亲自过去给它充电
So if the battery is low,
因此 如果电量很低
maybe we'd like the robot to know to wait for a can or to go to recharge its battery.
我们希望机器人能知道等待有人扔进易拉罐或前往充电基站
In the next few concepts,
在接下来的几个部分
we'll set up the problem with the ultimate goal of having
我们将构建该问题 最终目标是
the robots control equipment learn this behavior.
让机器人的控制设备能够学习这一行为